Hello, welcome to the next episode of Jayanti in Hindi.
Today we are going to learn a
concept, if you like this one, this
is a very important concept and this is such a
concept that people are very scared of it.
Forget B1, B2, even people learning C1 and C2 are
scared of which concepts. Don't worry,
we
will try to make it as easy as possible and
for that there are two things, firstly,
you will need a lot of practice for this, you have to
practice on this concept and
secondly, we are going to learn this in 2 parts,
first you are going to learn the job part, you have to
practice it a lot and then
after seven days, when we learn the next part, then you
can go with it. Okay, so first of all
we understand what is this concept,
why see, is it chicken, then at
least this is not ours,
friends, like when we
saw it earlier in English, in Hindi, it is
my son, my daughter, my children, mine, my mine, then
in English, what is this,
my, my, but when its
minor - my name used to come in the mind or give  That there is a
table of pain or happiness and prosperity. If you
look at it, in English and Hindi, the adjective like good
child, good good good good
good, you have to change it
like a change point. In Hindi, it is
good, good, good, good, it is the same
in German too. So, whatever it is, it will be like that.
Even unfortunately, it
goes a little bit further in German. If there are
three table fans for three people, if
I show them Bappa Tite, the first
type is definitely, but with, that means if you are
with Deedar Yadav, then the
meter reader of Tubelight will be separate. Then if it is
with an intertwined article, that means if it is a
festival, then there will be a table of clock, good
scooter. And if you do
not have any article, then if you are saying your directive, then there will be
voter card and I know it is a
little confusing, that is why you should do
it step by step. Okay, so there can be three
types of tables. This is for roti. Okay, so
what will we do today, the third table is the
article we will learn today. Okay,
and that will be confirmed for us. Then we will go and see the first two
tables, simple.  So the first
meaning is that direct discharge red ball
or it has come, it does not say Nader and the
pimple has come, it says Cleveland call Sanjay
Dutt when there is no article with it,
this is our first case technical, this is the third case from which
we are going to learn it by wearing it because if you
look at it, it is very simple, so the
paper for it will also be visible on the screen,
if you look at it calmly, then this is a very
similar table to our Dare Didar
duty, if you look at it with me, there is a
slight
difference in the press meet of the native and
a native in it, you will not use my book eyes like this,
then at the end of the second video,
I will tell you a sentence that in the
conditions of the right now
Neetu cancel report policies have to
remain in the nominal attractive, okay, so
if you look at that table, if officer, then
you will remember the mantra, it will hurt and if you
look at this table, this is not like this,
in ours it is exactly the same, right and the method of viewing is
also  It is exactly the same as
how we did it there. If we have come to Ujjwal Job
Wonderland and what did we say to it
that the ball itself is male and in this sentence it is
positive, that is why we went and saw it. We have to do the same here. If
we see all types of
sentences, then you will get a little
confidence. Okay, so first let's take our
basic sentence, in which this red
roses or red call rate in India, underline it,
say what is male and what is the subject of this sentence,
is nominated,
which is just portrait, nominative male,
see landing, that friend
parrot system router Buddhist stroll, very
simple message. The second red watch
under the tree, what is that female, you yourself are,
what is in the nominative sentence, that is
on the east route and similarly, if you have to do the
second red watch of a friend, the
center line between the nominative and neutral
cards is available, so rotate them above and rule them, let's
see in the city, red I have read all,
who is the subject, I have, so send that, what will happen
You tube mail this Howrah
route in the hair protein button
send a message that this Hubble roti and this rice roti
similarly if remind me again
what will happen after these quantum is done that look
neutral this Howrah route to rot is very
simple if you want to do it then how will you do it in
this play with Bob what does it mean
hence its route is very simple a
message if you want to do it play with
Red watch in wonderland RTO female speed
limit rotor similarly I play with Red car
dobo Newton speed limit rotate them onto
simple if you have understood this then you
know that or when adjective comes then
you understand it so I
am again subscribing to our channel what will you
say to this route in a very simple way a
basic what have you seen here that Baba just
like you were doing in English like how you did it in the same way
we did that whichever road itself
Rotterdam Roton whatever was going to be applied was going to be applied depending upon
our table
so this is for you right now without  If you understood the table in the article, then
what you have to do now, remember
as I said there is no need to worry about Net,
you are also not going to use it for the next 7 days
because our next part of it will be on
Mix Sunday,
I am going to come live on Wednesday and
what is going to happen to you for the next 7 days, right now every
day you should make at least 5 sentences of at least 5
sentences, this will give you
confidence and when you
will watch the video again on next Sunday, then at least
40 to 50 sentences of yours will be made,
so this addictive game of yours should be a good game without any
teaser, speed limit, rota, note to
or it should come, when it is perfect, then the
rest of the tables have to be seen, that is
very simple, we will easily
see that in the next class, there is no tension, what is very important for
everyone is that look I myself have made a mistake
with my
year basis, I laid down my test career first,
give me the Tibetan table of Chemistry on the same day, unknown  People get confused and
a fear arises that today there is something active between these two, that is why till
today we have been simple
plus mash the correct today
when I was not different, that is why I
filed it, by the way it is of a hotel, it is
not a big deal, so its conference people, first
learn to make this, after that the other two tables
we are going to see in this class, it is not a
big deal, if you are not
seeing it worthy, after a long time, if you are
watching this video, then I will increase you, immediately do
not watch the next video,
after watching this video, practice for seven days, only
when this table of yours becomes perfect, then you can go to the
next date, oh let's
revise a little, first of all what did
you say, what does it mean in the first date, that is, to
use attractive like
we used to do in Hindi, good boy, good
girl, well, it is not a new thing,
unfortunately, what is the table of the grandmother of the times, it has
three tables, if you
edit it with article then these, if you are
with article and without article, then
what did you learn today, we did without article  The
table was straightforward because it was very simple,
we had such a pain that it was shared with me,
MS back, Amazon, as I said, there is
no need to worry about the relative,
and as
we did in the cases, that
sentence laundering, you should see the laddu mail,
similarly we did the same here and then
we created the character system, voter ball, Ichhavar,
Rotan ball, speed limit, protem ball, I hope
you have understood this concept properly,
please adopt it because the
most important thing in this is to practice it,
please keep practicing,
as I said, we are going to meet this Wednesday
in live and next Sunday we will
take its second part, we will meet the remaining two tables on
Wednesday in live, thank you